4 Years Ago
Ah, thanks for always...
Clincity
Super delicious!
The next generation
water dispenser
The ultimate
natural spring
water to keep
you healthy
Call time
The secret to successful
walk-in sales is a smile!!
Thank you for your continued business!
（社員）
いつもご愛用いただき
感謝いたします
Is that so? We'll make
arrangements right away!
（社員）
ホントですか？
すぐにご準備いたします
Oh, no. No, no, no, no!
It's all thanks to you!
いや～ お客様のおかげですよ はい
Yes.
Clincity Inc.
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
じゃあ ここで
I'll take it.
Thank you so much!
（不動産屋）
ありがとうございます
Saturdays only
Just 2 hours in the morning!!
Working with a fun staff daily
to make every day exciting!
Make quick and easy money
Only weekdays and only until 5 PM
Hourly pay of 1,800 yen
Pick your location! Seeking staff for all 4 locations!!
We welcome newcomers with no experience!!
（霊幻）
ファ～ア 次は何するかな～
Working at a sushi shop!
Just packing sushi into containers or working the register!!
Applicants with no experience welcome!!
Once or twice a week, 4 hour shifts are perfectly OK!
A location in front of the station
is opening this month!!
[Seeking new staff]
Won't you try being a security guard?
I wonder what I should do now.
I got 20,000 just for
getting hired!
My hourly wage went up
a lot, too.
A hole-in-the-wall-place for adults
A place with a homey atmosphere
with plenty of other fellow part-timers!
Make plenty of friends!
I ended up renting this place
without having anything lined up.
とりあえずで借りちゃったからな～
Power Stone
You can become a
millionaire, too!!
Your life will change just by wearing it
It brings you good luck!
Mob Psycho
Poor, Lonely, Whitey
Telepathy Club
Body Improvement Club
Thirty-one...
（モブ）
31…
Thirty-two...
32　33…
Thirty-three...
Thirty-four...
34… うっ
Thirty-five...
35！
You did it! That's a new record!
（郷田(ごうだ)武蔵(むさし)）
やったな 新記録だ！
お前は強くなってるぞ 影山(かげやま)！
You've gotten stronger, Kageyama!
Your muscles are evolving!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
（隈川(くまかわ)）筋肉に変化が起きている！
（４人）ワッショイ ワッショイ
All your efforts are finally paying off!
（佐川(さがわ)）
努力の成果が
表れてきたんじゃないか？
Body improvement!!
1: Squats 30x5
2: Planks 1 minx5
3: Side Planks 10
4: Leg Up Lifts 10x3
5: Leg Raise 10x5
I thought his workouts were a waste of time,
（エクボ）
体力作りなんて
くだらねえと思ってたけど
but the way he's improving step by step
will make him more confident as well.
確かに こうやって
一歩ずつ進展していくのは
本人の自信につながるな
He even looks bolder.
雰囲気も
堂々としてきた印象がある
Potato
Demons
Mob-kun's having fun,
being tossed in the air.
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
胴上げ 楽しそうね モブ君
Oh, I know!
あ～ そうだ！
Why don't you toss him, too?
よかったら
こいつも胴上げしてやってよ
It's his birthday today.
今日 誕生日なんだって！
Huh? No, that's okay.
（雉子林(きじばやし)）
は？　いや いいよ
Is it your birthday, Kijibayashi?
雉子林 誕生日なのか？
ま… まあな
Y-Yeah...
（郷田）
おお そいつはめでたい！
祝ってやろう！
Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
What a joyous day! Let us celebrate!
（隈川）
あっ 部長
俺も先週 誕生日でした
Oh, hey, President.
It was my birthday last week, too.
What? It was?!
なに 隈川もか？
Then why don't we throw a birthday party?
（猿田(さるた)）
よかったら誕生会やりましょうよ
How about we all go to a family restaurant?
みんなでファミレスなんて
どうっすか？
What a nice idea, Saruta!
（犬川(いぬかわ)）
猿田 ナイスアイディア！
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
What's this?
（客）
こちらは？
ウユニ塩湖から採取された
非常に貴重な岩塩で
It's extremely rare rock salt obtained
from the Uyuni Salt Flats,
除霊効果に優れて…
and it's excellent for exorcisms!
（携帯の着信音）
（霊幻）ちょっと失礼
Excuse me for a moment.
はい “霊とか相談所”
Hello, this is the Spirits and
Such Consultation Office.
え？　凍った豆腐の霊ですか？
What? Frozen tofu spirits?
Of course, I've heard of them!
聞いたことがありますね
お任せください
Leave it to me.
I'm getting one job after another lately...
（霊幻）
しかし最近 依頼が絶えないな
Guspo
Restaurant
Happy birthday, happy birthday,
Kijibayashi and Kumakawa!
（郷田たち）
♪ ハッピバースデー
ハッピバースデー
Happy birthday, happy birthday,
happy birthday to you!
（一同）♪ おめでとう～
（拍手）
We got the drink bar,
so let's drink until we've had our fill!
（志村(しむら)）
ドリンクバー
飲んで飲んで飲みまくろうぜ！
I never thought you'd stick with the Body
Improvement Club for so long, Mob-kun.
それにしても
モブ君が肉体改造部を
こんなに続けるなんてね
I thought he'd run away immediately.
すぐ逃げ出すと思ってました
Kageyama's pretty persistent.
（佐川）
影山は なかなか執念深いよ
Do you have some huge goal
you want to accomplish?
強い目標みたいなものが
あるのかな？
If you keep at it for another six months,
（志村）
あと半年も頑張れば
中学２年の平均値に届くと思うよ
I think you'll reach the level of an
average second-year middle schooler.
Nah.
いや 影山の見据える最終地点は
その程度じゃないはずだ
I'm sure Kageyama has his sights set
on a much loftier goal.
俺たちも うかうかしてると
負けてしまうぞ！
If we let our guards down,
he might surpass us before we know it!
好きな子を振り向かせたい
だけなのにね
All he wants is for the girl he likes
to look his way, really.
最初は それだけだったけど 今は…
That was it at first, but now...
By the way, Mob-kun,
I hope you haven't forgotten.
っていうか モブ君
忘れてないでしょうね？
You're supposed to help me
find other telepaths.
テレパシー能力者探しのこと
Oh. You're still looking for them?
あ… まだ探してたんですか？
Of course I am! What do you think
the point of the Telepathy Club is?!
当然でしょ！
脳感電波部を何だと思ってるわけ？
（犬川）そんなことより…
（暗田）そんなこと？
More importantly, why don't
we all go to karaoke?
"More importantly"?!
（犬川）
このあと みんなで
カラオケにでも行きませんか？
Huh? Karaoke?
えっ カラオケ？
なんだ
お前 行ったことないのか？
What? You've never gone before?
Let's go, then. A chance like this
won't come along very often.
じゃあ 行こうぜ！
こんな日も そうそうないだろう！
Well, if you insist...
そんなに言うなら しかたないわね
What should I sing?
（暗田）
何 歌おうかしら
Feeling shy, Mob?
恥ずかしいのか モブ？
歌っちまえば どうってことねえよ
You'll be fine once you start singing.
No, I was just thinking it's been a while
since I've done something like this.
いや こんなの久しぶりだなって…
こんなふうに
みんなで遊びに行くのって
Just hanging out with people.
I-It's so much fun...
（モブ）
た… 楽しい
Incoming call
Master Reigen
Menu
Hello?
Oh hey, Mob.
（霊幻）
あっ モブ？
ちょっと悪霊に手こずっててさあ
There's an evil spirit
giving me some trouble.
I mean, I could totally deal with it myself,
but there's been so much work lately.
いや
俺１人でも余裕ではあるんだが
最近 立て込んでてな
I'd rather not use too much of my power...
力の放出は避けたいっていうか…
モブ？
Mob?
Master, could you handle
things on your own today?
今日は師匠
１人でやってくれませんか？
Huh?
い… いきなり呼び出すの
やめてほしいって―
I-I've asked you many times before
not to summon me on such short notice.
いつも言ってるじゃないですか
What are you talking about?
I bet you're free, anyway.
（霊幻）
なに言ってるんだ　どうせ暇だろ？
Is there a reason you can't show up?
来れない理由があるのか？
There's a client who really
needs your help here.
こっちには
困ってる依頼人がいるんだぜ
I'll be waiting for you,
so try not to take too long.
待ってるからな
できるだけ早めに頼む
どうした 影山？
What's the matter, Kageyama?
Must be that shady-ass master of yours again.
また例のうさんくさい師匠ね？
A sudden job came in, so I won't
be able to go to karaoke.
急なバイトが入って
カラオケには行けなくなりました
I'm really sorry for missing out
on your birthdays.
すみません
せっかくの誕生日なのに
Oh, don't worry about us.
いや いいよ　俺たちのことなんて
気にするな　十分だ
Yeah, you've done plenty.
Some things take priority over others.
物事には優先順位がある
しかたないさ
It's okay. We understand.
The ghost of a man who hit his head
on a block of frozen tofu and died?
（依頼人）
凍った豆腐の角に頭を打ちつけて
死んだ男の霊が出るとのウワサが
That rumor was true?
本当だったとは…
How about I make you think of me
every time you see a block of tofu?!
（悪霊）
豆腐を見るたびに
俺を思い出させてやろうか？
（２人）
ひい～！
Please, hurry up and exorcise him!
（依頼人）
早く除霊してください！
ご安心ください
急いで私の弟子を向かわせてます
Have no fear.
I have my disciple heading over immediately.
（依頼人たち）
え？　ああっ ハア…
You're a lifesaver, Mob.
助かったぜ モブ
（霊幻）♪ ふん ふふん ふふっ…
（足音）
ん？　どうした？
What's wrong?
Even I have school and a private life.
（モブ）
僕にだって
学校やプライベートがあるんだから
So please, stop summoning me
out of the blue.
いきなり呼び出すのは
もう やめてください
A private life? Just working out
in that club of yours, right?
プライベートって
せいぜい
筋トレの部活くらいじゃないのか？
Or did you fall for another
person jokingly asking you out?
それか またデート詐欺か何かに
引っ掛かったのか？
You get taken advantage of so easily.
すぐ利用されんだから
Grow up, for crying out loud.
成長しねえな お前はよ～
I don't know what you were doing
with your schoolmates,
同級生と何やってたが知らんが
そいつらは お前の理解者なのか？
but do they really understand you?
Come on, we're saving lives here!
こっちゃ 人助けだぞ？　人助け！
お前が俺を手伝うことには
大きな意義がある
You're making a difference in
the world by helping me out!
Not to mention, I'm your master!
しかも 俺はお前の師匠！
I'm one of the biggest reasons
you're able to control your powers!
お前が自分の力を
コントロールできているのは
実は俺のおかげでもある
Listen up...
いいか？
関わる相手を選べよ モブ！
Choose your social circle wisely, Mob!
除霊バイトが
できなくなるくらいだったら
If they're going to get in the way of
your exorcism job, get rid of them!
片方を切り捨てろ！
They don't actually care about you.
どうせ お前のことなんか
大切に思っちゃいねえよ
They're just having fun
mocking someone as wimpy as you.
弱い人間を内心でバカにして
楽しんでんだよ
（モブ）
違う！
That's not true!
I-I might've said too much there...
まあ
それは言い過ぎたかもしれんが…
They aren't mocking me.
バカになんてしてない
R-Right...
お… おう
きっと
霊幻師匠の言うことが
I'm starting to understand that not
everything you say is true, Master.
正しいとは限らないんだ
Dug his own grave
Shit. I messed up...
（霊幻）
あ… ミスッた！
な… 何 言ってんだ モブ
C-Come on now, Mob! You must be tired!
疲れてんだな
Let's get some ramen on the way back.
ラーメンでも食って帰ろうぜ
I'm not being mocked, nor am
I easily taken advantage of.
（モブ）
僕はバカにされてもないし
簡単に利用もされない
Reception
The New Star of
the 21st Century
Reigen Arataka's
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Damn it, Mob...
（霊幻）
モブの野郎
I'd promised this client in advance...
今日は事前に約束してたのに
He finally decided not to show up.
いよいよバックレやがったな
I guess I really did say too much yesterday.
やはり 昨日は
ちょっと嫌な感じで言い過ぎたか？
But then again...
（霊幻）
いや でも あいつが俺以外に
悩みを相談できる相手なんて
He shouldn't have anyone he can talk
to about his problems other than me.
いるはずがない
If he cuts ties with me,
he's going to end up alone again.
俺と関わりを断てば
また元の孤独に戻る
There's nothing to worry about.
He'll be back here. I know it.
案ずるな
あいつは必ずここに戻ってくる
（影山 律(りつ)）
あれ？　兄さん
Huh? Nii-san?
You're home early today.
今日は帰りが早いんだね
Welcome home, Ritsu.
おかえり 律
しばらく師匠の所には
行かないことにしたんだ
I've decided not to go to
Master's place for a while.
いいと思うけど 急にどうして？
That's fine and all,
but what brought this on?
They had a fight. He cut ties with him.
ケンカだ
もう ヤツとは決別したのさ
That's not it. But I gave it a lot of
thought and made my decision.
そんなんじゃないけど
いろいろ考えて決めた
僕は今まで―
I've been blindly following what
Master Reigen says way too often.
霊幻師匠の言葉に乗っかりすぎてた
I felt like things went better that way,
so it was easier for me.
それで
全部がうまくいくような気がして
なんか楽だったんだ
でも…
But...
Grow up, for crying out loud.
成長しねえな お前はよ～
それだけじゃ良くない
ことに気付いたから
I realized that I can't just
keep relying on him,
so I thought I'd reconsider
what I want to do a bit more.
もう少し
自分のやりたいことを
考え直してみる
Wanna play some video games for once?
たまにはゲームでもする？
Too bad, Reigen.
（エクボ）
残念だったな 霊幻
It's your own fault for messing up.
ボロを出したお前が悪い
（依頼人）
いや～
つきものが落ちたような気分です
I feel like I've sweat off
whatever was lurking over me.
Coral steam yoga is the best.
珊瑚(さんご)スチームヨガ 最高ですね～
Glad to hear it.
それは何よりです
Thank goodness it wasn't a real spirit.
（霊幻）
よかった　本物じゃなくて
4 Years Ago
Why am I so surprised, though?
でも そうだよな
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Spirits Consultation Office
I basically built this business
from the ground up all by myself.
この稼業は元々
俺の身ひとつで成立してきたんだ
Option A — Trial Course
A Mere 2,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 3,980 yen.
Option B — Serious Course
A Mere 5,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 8,980 yen
Recommended
Option C — All-Out Course
A Mere 12,000 yen (Tax Excluded)
Outside of Offer Period: 19,880 yen
Refer us to a friend now and get an extra 5% reduction!!
Also get an add-on exorcism for 20% off!!
Why would I be in any trouble
if Mob decides to not show up?
モブがいなくて困ることなんか
あるか？
I just need to continue focusing
on the jobs I can do by myself.
今までどおり
俺は 自分の手に負えることだけ
要領よく こなしておけばいいんだ
I can let the real psychics
deal with actual spirits.
霊退治は本物に任せればいいし
Yeah! Now I can reduce labor costs,
そうだよ！　人件費だって削れるし
and I won't have to hear
about his teenage dilemmas.
ガキの思春期相談だって
聞かずに済む
時間は有限だしな
I only have so much time in a day.
I should use it to study
and learn more about the world.
その分
勉強したり 見聞を広めるべきだ
Hey, I'm becoming rather
optimistic about this.
なんか
スゲえ前向きになってきたぞ！
Sorry, Mob. You probably
weren't expecting this,
悪いな モブ
お前の計算外だろうが
俺は全然 悔しくないぞ！
but I'm not sad about this at all.
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
I'm sure you're probably feeling
pretty lonely right about now.
お前は今頃
寂しがっているだろうがな
Mob Psycho
Salt
I'm sure Mob's really regretting this by now.
（霊幻）
今頃 モブのヤツ
ひどく後悔してるだろうな
Maybe he feels awkward about talking to me.
意地を張って
気まずくなってるのかもな
I'm mature enough to understand,
so it's not like I'd even care.
大人な俺は事情も察せるし
気にしてないというのに
Super popular!!
Impossible! Mob looks like
he's actually having fun!
バカな！　あのモブが
楽しそうにしている！
He actually had friends?!
あんな友達がいたのか？
What the hell are you hiding for, dumbass?
なに隠れてんだ てめえ？
うお～！　エクボ？
Yosokaze!
Dimple!
I-I'm not hiding at all!
かっ 隠れてなんかいねえよ
You don't need to worry about Mob anymore.
（エクボ）
モブのほうは心配すんなよ
楽しそうだから
He's having fun.
Well, too bad I'm not
actually worried at all!
あいにくだが
心配なんかしてないな
Good to hear.
そりゃあ よかった
Shigeo doesn't seem to be
concerned about you at all.
茂夫(しげお)は お前のこと
全く何にも気にしてないみたいだし
It's rather peaceful.
とても平和だな
What?!
へっ お前はいいのかよ エクボ？
Are you okay with this, Dimple?
What do you mean?
（エクボ）
何がだ？
The more he stays away from me,
the less he'll use his powers.
俺から遠ざかれば
モブは
ますます能力を使わなくなるぞ
お前は
ただの中学生の金魚のフンを
Do you want to be an ordinary
middle schooler's pet forever?
この先もずっと
やっていくのかよ？
そりゃ 平和だな
Guess that would be pretty peaceful.
Pork roast
Paella
comes with a salad
I think you wanted to use Mob's powers
to do something, but sucks to be you.
（霊幻）
モブの力を利用して
何かしたかったようだが
残念だったな
Now that Mob's decided to
lead such a mundane life,
何も起きない日常に
身を置くことを選んだモブに
he's of no use to anybody!
利用価値はもう ない！
I hope you have fun following
around a normal middle schooler.
ただの中学生にひっついて
せいぜい楽しく過ごすといい
I, on the other hand, will be
moving on to the next stage!
その間に 俺は
次のステージに行かせてもらうぜ
Well, I'm glad to see
you're doing all right.
まっ 相変わらず元気そうで何より
If you can crack jokes like that,
I guess there's no need to worry.
そんなギャグが言えるくらいなら
心配ねえな
Who knows? We may never
see each other again.
もう二度と会うこともないかもな
（霊幻）
ハア
Guess I'll update the homepage.
ホームページの更新でもするか
Karaoke
Huh? Aren't we going home?
（モブ）
あれ？　帰らないの？
Weren't we giving up looking
for telepaths today?
テレパシー能力者 探すの
今日はもう諦めるって…
You couldn't go the other day
because of work, right?
お前 こないだ
バイトで行けなかっただろ？
せっかくだし 入ろうぜ
We're here anyway, so let's go.
Karaoke
You'll be able to sense a telepath
if they're nearby, right?
（暗田）
超能力者が近くにいれば
センサー作動するんでしょ？
Then you can do it while you're singing, too.
歌いながらでも
いいんじゃないの？
But wait! I'm not mentally prepared!
いや ちょっと心の準備が…
Oh, come on. Get in there.
（暗田）
いいから ほら 入った入った！
Newbie Idol's Blog Gets Flamed
A newbie idol's blog got flamed, huh?
（霊幻）
“新人アイドル ブログ炎上”か
ふ～ん
I guess I haven't checked
Friendbook in a while.
そういや しばらく“friend book”
チェックしてなかったな
In this day and age, you can connect
with the people you know at any time.
今はＳＮＳで
いつでも知人と交流できるから
Talk about convenient.
便利な時代だよな～
お！　メッセージ来てるじゃん
Hey, I have a message!
Sorry for not reading it sooner.
I've just been so busy.
放置してて悪かったな～
私生活が忙しくて…
Search
Story
Archive | Settings
Who could it be? Maybe it's
the one I met at the mixer...
誰だろ？　あいつかな？
高校んときの…
Notification
Mark all as read | Settings
Congratulations!
It's your birthday today.
People you might know
Upload a photo or video, or post something
Oh, right...
ん？　そうか
I totally forgot.
すっかり忘れてたな
Congratulations!
It's your birthday today.
Notification
Mark all as read | Settings
Congratulations!
It's your birthday today.
See messages from your friends wishing you a
happy birthday (0 messages)
Seriously?
マジかよ
Huh? A message?
（霊幻）
ん？　メール？
To Arataka – From Mom
Save me! Kokkuri-san won't leave my house!
Main
Social
To Arataka – From Mom
Save me! Kokkuri-san won't leave my house! Save me, please! Please come to...
Exorcism request – Hello? Are you a psychic? My body feels so heavy lately...
Perv Master – We got a fresh batch of pervy videos for you! Now you can be a perv master...
You're a fake – I'll curse you... CurseCurseCurseCurseCurseCurseCurseCurse
Spirit photo – I ended up taking one. Could you do something about it?
To Reigen Arataka
Happy birthday. How are you doing?
How's work? Are you still in that shady business?
Remember our neighbors, the Kobayashis?
I heard their oldest son got married just last month.
You should hurry up and find a secure job.
You still have a chance. You're still only 28.
If you want another chance at life,
you should probably make a decision fast...
Make sure you take care of yourself.
Here's my gift to you.
Open file attachment
Looking for staff
Whitey Recruitment Invitation
No experience?
No problem!
A cheerful and fun workplace
Have you ever heard of a company called "Whitey"
that works hard to make the world a better place to live?
If you haven't, let me tell you all about our company.
It's not a difficult job, but it's definitely not an easy
job, either! But if you have the determination to work
hard, we'll welcome you with open arms!
Contact us 24 hours a day!
Apply by
Email
or Fax!
1. Name 2. Phone number 3. Address
4. Desired hours 5. Desired office
Please make sure you include
this information when you apply.
（２人）
♪ 電 電 電波で脳内メルト
Melt, melt, melt your brain
with electronic waves
Still training to get a real feel of it
Are you having fun?
So all together now
（犬川）
楽しいか？
I think so?
多分
Melancholy!
（２人）
♪ メランコリー
You have no rhythm, do you, Mob-kun?
モブ君 リズム感ないのね
Yeah! Wahoo!
（犬川）
いぇい　わっほー！
Correct.
はい
Reunion
Happy Trails
Ooh, Arataka-chan!
（マスター）
あら 新隆ちゃん
Welcome. It's been too long.
いらっしゃい！
かなり久しぶりじゃない
Hey, it's Reigen-san! Reigen-sensei is here!
（男性客）
霊幻さんだ！　霊幻先生が来たぞ！
Sensei! Come sit over here, Sensei!
（女性客）
先生！　先生 こっち座って ほら！
One lemon sour...
レモンサワー　サワー多めで
Extra on the sour.
Should you be drinking?
お酒 大丈夫なの？
Yeah.
The regulars here are a bunch of people
who'd fall for pyramid schemes or fake cults.
（霊幻）
ここの常連は―
マルチ商法やエセ宗教などに
引っ掛かりやすい体質の者ばかり
People like that who want someone
to vent their troubles to
そういった類いの悩みや愚痴を
誰かに聞いてもらいたい連中が
relieve their stress at this bar.
Happy Trails
ここでストレスを吐き出していく
It's basically a gold mine
for someone like me.
俺みたいな業者にとっては
格好の釣堀
It's a place where a bunch
of weak people gather.
弱い人間の たまり場だ
Hear me out, Reigen-san!
聞いてくれ 霊幻さん
The other day, this really
pretty girl talked to me.
この前ね きれいなねえちゃんに
話しかけられて
When I followed her, she led
me to some art exhibit...
ついていったら
絵画の展示しててさあ
You were taken to an exhibit where a copy
of a famous painting was on display.
名画のコピーの展覧会に
連れていかれたんだな
It's a dating scheme.
デート商法だ
I'll hear them out and give them
some random words of advice.
（霊幻）
相談を聞いて
適当な助言をするだけで
Apparently, that's enough
for them to respect me.
やたら慕われる
Maybe they're... almost like friends to me.
俺にとって
友人… に近いのか？
It's... my birthday today.
（霊幻）
俺 今日 誕生日なんだ
Well, happy birthday.
おめでとう
Happy birthday, Sensei.
先生 おめでとうございま～す
Happy birthday.
おめでとう
どうも
Thanks.
This is the perfect time to bring
this up since it's your birthday!
（女性客）
誕生日だったら ちょうどよかった
I have this amazing pillow I got
from this extra special connection.
今ね 特別なルートから紹介された
いい枕があってね
低反発でぐっすり眠れて
定価12万円が…
It's memory foam, so you'll sleep like
a baby! It's worth 120,000 yen, but...
Arataka-chan, this is your
first drink, isn't it?
新隆ちゃん まだ１杯でしょ？
Your face is all red. Are you all right?
顔 真っ赤よ！　大丈夫？
Nope.
（霊幻）
ダメだな
えい！
あっ！　ど… どうしたのよ
Wh-What's wrong?
Tab, please.
お会計
Well, that backfired.
（霊幻）
逆効果だったな
I was thinking that I wanted
to talk to someone... anyone.
誰とでもいいから
会話しようなんて…
I guess I don't have any friends.
俺って友達いなかったんだな
But I didn't even put any alcohol in it...
（マスター）
アルコール抜いといたのに
（霊幻）
おう うっ ううっ…
おえ～
This situation's not good...
（霊幻）
この状況はマズい
I'm going in a very bad direction.
マズい流れに乗ろうとしている！
この俺が！
Me, of all people!
“この俺”って…
Wait... Me?
そもそも 俺は
I mean what...
What...
俺は何だ？
What am I?
I guess I'm just going to have to...
（霊幻）
俺も なるしかない
become somebody.
何者かに！
After ending up alone and getting over it,
Reigen made a huge change.
（ナレーション）
単独になり 吹っ切れた霊幻は
明確な変化を起こした
I, Reigen Arataka, shall accept this job!
その依頼
この霊幻新隆が引き受けた！
New Reigen Arataka
Spirits and Such
Consultation Office
He started beautifying the city,
（ナレーション）
町の清掃活動を始めたり
live-streamed exorcisms online,
除霊の様子をネット公開したり
Don't tell people personal information they don't
need to know        No payments upfront
Don't sign any contracts
Vases | Holy water | Salt
Cooling off...
held free seminars and even
offered people life counseling,
無料講座や人生相談も始めたりして
broadening his field of work.
活躍の場を広げつつも
Noritama-san's Review
Post a review
"Spirits and Such Consultation Office" is wonderful.
The man in charge, Reigen Arataka-san, is a true psychic.
Because of him, my body feels much lighter, and I can feel my luck improving.
User ID: 2875934091
Flat Tire-san's Review
Post a review
Reigen Arataka-san is one of the few real psychics.
He listened to me, gave me advice, and I finally met my match.
Thank you so much.
User ID: 3829573019
However, he continued to execute his
usual exorcism jobs with vigor.
今までどおり
依頼も精力的にこなしていった
Stray Cat of the Dawn's Review
Post a review
I'm so thankful that I just can't stop crying.
No one was willing to help me out, but Reigen...
I might just be falling in love...
User ID: 867840127
All of our satisfied customers
Among his most recent jobs,
there was a rumor that the Player Killer
中でも 超有名オンラインゲーム
「ファンタジー地獄」の
Fantasy Hell
from the super-popular online game,
Fantasy Hell, was actually a ghost.
プレイヤーキラーは
正体が幽霊とウワサされており
It was a difficult job that many
other psychics declined to take.
多くの霊能力者が断念した難問依頼
We asked Shinra Banshomaru
what he thought
I've heard of it, but don't even bother.
（森羅万象丸(しんらばんしょうまる)）
聞いたことはあるが やめておけ
It's not something we can handle.
我々の手に負えるものじゃない
Our spiritual power can't
do anything inside a game.
システムの中にまで
霊能力は届かない
…だろ？
Right?
Meaning it was a target that even
Mob wouldn't be able to exorcise.
（ナレーション）
つまり モブですら除霊する手段を
持たない事案だったのだ
However, Reigen used multiple accounts
and stayed up late many nights,
しかし 霊幻は複数のアカウントで
連日 深夜まで
レベル上げと武器強化を繰り返し
repeatedly leveling up and
strengthening his weapons...
おとりを餌に
幽霊プレイヤーを囲い込み
He then baited the ghost
player and surrounded it,
then beat the crap out of him.
袋だたきを開始
And then, finally,
he succeeded in the exorcism.
そして ついに除霊に成功する
Y-You're amazing!
You actually exorcised him!
（依頼人１）
すっ すごい！
本当に除霊できたんですね
But how?
（依頼人２）
一体どうやって？
Well, I am a psychic...
霊能力者ですから
Shit. I made too many in-game purchases,
and now I'm in the red...
（霊幻）
くっ 課金し過ぎて赤字か～！
Because of this successful job,
（ナレーション）
この成功をきっかけに
the agency's popularity continued to rise.
事務所の名前は
どんどん話題になっていった
Popularity
I Love Online Games@netgman
Reigen Arataka is the real deal!
He exorcised the online ghost!
#FantasyHell
#SpiritsandSuchConsultationOffice
Popularity
Headlines | Japanese | International | Economy | Entertainment | Sports | IT & Science | Life | Local
The Online Ghost Has Finally Been Exorcised!
A True Psychic Actually Exists
Do you all believe in ghosts? Even better.
Do you believe in psychics who fight these
ghosts? Currently, there is a certain psychic that's
sending the Internet into a stir. According to the
posts, this psychic, Reigen Arataka, was not only
able to actually exorcise a ghost, but one that
existed in an online game.
Usually, I would dismiss someone like this as
just an attention seeker, and write
some comments putting him in his place. But this
time, unlike others...
Someone eventually started
誰かが霊幻を
“調味市(ちょうみし)の兄”などと呼び始めると
Popularity
calling Reigen "the Bro of Seasoning City,"
Reigen Arataka Fansite
A Blog About the "Bro of Seasoning City"
This site is about the "Spirits and Such Consultation Office"...
Popularity
Reigen Arataka... There's no doubt about it...
The man might seriously be a god.
59 reactions
and his popularity skyrocketed so much,
その知名度は加速し
Popularity
he even got interviewed for a magazine.
雑誌からのインタビューを
受けるまでになった
Popularity
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
And a few days after that...
更に その数日後
Gozz TV Director Binwan Taro
T-TV?!
（霊幻）
テッ テレビ？
You mean I'm that popular?
そんなに注目されているのか？
俺は…
（ディレクター）
霊幻先生のウワサを
たまたま耳にしたプロデューサーが
One of our producers happened to hear
about you and wanted you on our show.
“是非 番組に”と…
Gozz TV                                 Program Proposal
Supernatural Detective!
Do Spiritual Powers Actually Exist?
Special
A national broadcast?
（霊幻）
全国放送か
If you manage to get popular on TV,
うまくテレビで人気を得られれば
you'll immediately shoot to
the top of the psychic world.
一気に霊能界の大物ですよ！
フフフ…
One week later
Supernatural Detective...
（司会者）
「怪奇探偵」
Do Spiritual Powers Actually Exist? Special!
「霊能力は実在するのか
スペシャル！」
Supernatural Detective
Special!!
生放送でお送りしてます！
We are live tonight!
I, Ebihara Morizo, am your host,
Host
Ebihara Morizo
司会は私
海老原(えびはら)モリ蔵(ぞう)と
Mogi Tatsuya
ゲストに
ＳＦ学者 茂木(もぎ)達也(たつや)さん
joined by our guests, sci-fi researcher
Mogi Tatsuya-san and idol SATAKE-san.
アイドル
ＳＡＴＡＫＥさん
（２人）
お願いします
こんにちは～
Thanks for having me.
Hello!
Jodo Kirin
Reigen Arataka
We also have some psychics
with us here today.
（司会者）
そして 霊能者の方々に
来ていただいてます！
It's a pleasure to have you on the program.
本日は
よろしくお願いします！
The pleasure's all mine.
よろしくお願いします
Holy crap... I'm actually on TV.
（霊幻）
スゲえ～ 俺 テレビに出てるよ
Everything's going so smoothly.
トントン拍子に
盛り上がってる感じだ
Today, we've invited someone who claims
to be possessed by an evil spirit.
Do Spiritual Powers Actually Exist!?
Special!!
今回は
悪い霊に取りつかれたという人物を
スタジオに招待！
We will have our experts exorcise
them live on our program!
先生方には 生放送中に
除霊をしていただきます！
Come on, now...
（霊幻）
おいおい もし全国放送で
格好よくキメちゃったら
If I actually pull this off like
a rock star on national TV,
maybe I'll get even more fans...
ファンとか
できちゃうんじゃないの？
All right. I'm nervous, but I'm
going to show them what I've got!
よっしゃ！
"...nervous, but I'm going to show them what
I've got!" is what you're thinking, isn't it?
（霊幻と浄堂麒麟(じょうどうきりん)）
緊張するけど ここは
気合いの入れどころだな
（浄堂）
とか思ってるだろう
That ego of yours is going to
deflate soon enough, you fool!
今のうちに
せいぜい浮かれてろ
バカめ！
I'm the one who mentioned you to
one of the TV station's producers!
お前をテレビ局のプロデューサーに
紹介したのは
この私だ！
My disciples told me about
what happened that day!
あの日のことは
弟子から聞いているぞ
Anti-Possession Jumping Knee Strike
They told me how you had the nerve to
nail me with a jumping knee strike!
この浄堂麒麟に
飛び膝蹴りを入れたことを！
I'm going to make you pay dearly!
簡単には許さんぞ～
I'll make damn sure you
regret what you've done!
徹底的に後悔させてやる！
（霊幻）
21世紀の新星 霊幻新隆
テレビ初出演！
The new star of the 21st
century, Reigen Arataka!
He makes his TV debut!
And on national TV!
しかも 全国放送！
フッ ついに俺もここまで来たか
I've finally come this far.
Just you watch, Mob!
見てろよ モブ！
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 7:
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
第７話
“追い込み　正体”
"Cornered
~True Identity~."
The blu-rays? An even better decision.
Cornered
~True Identity~
ブルーレイ？　更に正しい判断です